In the last lecture, we already used our utility function update object to make our reducers leaner
Zayflatclarmz ortak admmz dardan tedarik ederek daha yaln hale getirmek iin, faydal ilevi gncelleme nesnesini
by outsourcing a common step
kullandmz son dersi sonlandrn.
we repeated all over the place into a utility function.
Her yerde bir fayda fonksiyonuna tekrarlarz.
Now our reducer cases actually are pretty lean with that, in the counter reducer they can't get much leaner.
imdi redktr durumlarmz aslnda gzel Linville, hesaplarda REDUCE-IT'de daha az ya alabiliyorlar ve en
In the result reducer, we at least have one of the cases with an extra step where we update the
azndan diziyi gncellediimiz fazladan bir adm atm salam bir yapmc
array.
olduklarn sylyorlar.
Some developers not all of them but some like to have very lean cases where you essentially have case,
Baz gelitiriciler hepsini deil, bazlar aslnda byk / kk harfli durumda bulunmaktan holanyor; burada byk /
colon and then one function you call,
kk harf ayrm ve ardnz bir ilev var.
obviously we still need to run our logic but they like to outsource this into a function, so that the
Akas, yine de mantm altrmamz gerekiyor, ancak switch case ifadesinin ok yaln olmas iin bunu bir fonksiyona
switch case statement is very lean.
d kaynaktan yklemekten holanyorlar.
This has one major advantage, if a switch case statement looks like in the counter reducer,
Anahtar kutusu bildirimi kar redktre benziyorsa, nemli bir avantaj vardr.
we can quickly see what happens in each reducer or at least where we handle something.
Her reticide neler olduunu veya en azndan bir eyler zerinde altmz hzl bir ekilde grebiliriz.
So we see all cases on one page so to say. For the result.js file, that would mean that we can
Dolaysyla, tek bir sayfadaki tm davalar gryoruz, bu nedenle bu sonbaharda yaplan sonulara gre,
outsource this logic here into its own function,
bu mant burada kendi iine yerletirebileceksiniz demek.
that function goes into the same file.
Bu ilev ayn dosyaya girer.
So there I will simply add a new function outside of the reducer function
Bylece indiricinin dnda sadece yeni bir fonksiyon ekleyeceim.
obviously and I will name it deleteResult
Akas ve silmek iin ad vereceim.
.
Sonu.
The convention should be to use the action type as the name, though not in all caps but in camel case.
Szleme, eylem trn ad olarak deil, byk harflerle deil deve haliyle kullanmaktr.
So deleteResult and there I get my state and I need to get my action,
Yani gerek anlamda tuz ve orada durumumu alyorum ve eyleme gemem lazm.
so essentially the same data I get in the reducer.
Aslnda redktrde elde ettiim ayn veri.
Now here I wanted to use ES6 arrow function syntax, so I'll do that
imdi bunu 6 ok ilev szdizimi olarak kullanmak istiyorum, bu yzden bunu yapacam.
and in this function, I now basically execute what I did before in the switch case statement.
Ve bu ileve, temelde switch case ifadesinde daha nce yaptklarm uyguluyorum.
So in my case, I'll update the array, I'll put that method in there or that code in there, into the deleteResult
hepsi orada bu yntemi koymak dizisini gnceller veya oradaki kodu silme sonucu ilevi haline getirir.
function.
Dolaysyla benim durumumda
Now in the end, here in this function I of course need to return the updated state still
imdi burada bu fonksiyonda gncellenmi hali hala dndrmek gerekiyor.
so I will also grab that code from my deleteResult case and call updated object with the state
Bu yzden de silme saldr durumumdan bu kodu grep edeceim ve gncellenmi nesneyi bir durumla aracam.
and then basically doing the same as I did before in the switch case statement,
Ve temel olarak switch case deyiminde daha nce yaptm gibi davranyorlar.
and that's exactly the idea behind this helper functions.
Ve onun tam da onun yardmnn veya ilevlerinin ardndaki fikir.
You put your old code into them and then, I can just call deleteResult and return that here.
Eski kodunuzu onlara koydunuz ve daha sonra lead n-tuzunu arayp burada veriyi geri veremem.
So since deleteResult returns map to that object,
Bu nedenle Rosol'u sildikten sonra nesne olan haritay dndrr.
I can simply return deleteResult here,
Silme sonucunu burada geri getirebilirim.
just calling it like this
Sadece byle aryorlar.
and of course I have to pass on this state and action because both is needed in that function.
Tabii ki devlete ve eyleme gemek zorundaym nk her ikisi de bu ilevde gerekli.
With that we got a leaner reducer here too, let me remove the comments, doesn't get leaner than that,
Bundan dolay, burada daha zayf olmayacak ekilde yorumlar kaldrmamza izin vermek iin yasz bir indirgeyici var.
we can now also write the inline next to the colon if we wanted to, to have it really lean and only have
Ayrca, eer gerekten yaslanm olmanz ve her satrda bir kutuya sahip olmanz isteseydik, iki nokta
one case per line.
st ste yanndaki satrda yazabiliriz.
And this is all optional,
Ve hepsi istee baldr.
it is a way of creating very lean switch case statements though which make it easy to see which cases
Bu, belirli bir azaltcda hangi vaka ile uratnz kolaylatran ve bu yaklamn bir
you're handling in a given reducer and that can be the advantage of this approach.
avantaj olabilen ok temiz anahtar kutusu ifadeleri oluturmak iin bir yoldur.